Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Stereographs 1850-1964 (Bulk 1860-1900) PR 65
New-York Historical Society
- Geographic, 1850-1964
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Streets, Avenues -- Ninth, 1940-1958 (Box 41)
    Ninth Avenue: between Gansevoort and Little West 12th Streets, elevated tracks overhead; north from 23rd Street, a bar, a drugstore and other businesses, below apartments.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Streets, Avenues -- Amsterdam, 1956 (Box 41)
    Identifier:PR-065-0475
    Amsterdam Avenue north from 65th Street.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Streets, Avenues -- Lexington, 1872-1959 (Box 41)
    Identifier:PR-065-0476
    Lexington Avenue: Cows grazing at Lexington and 45th Street; looking north on Lexington from 27th, 38th, 54th and 70th, showing apartments, the Chrysler Building, the Church, and businesses; looking northeast from 41st, showing parking lot, hotel and office buildings; Peerless Cameras at 43rd and Lexington; office building under construction at 47th Street.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Streets, Avenues -- Madison, 1956 (Box 41)
    Identifier:PR-065-0477
    Madison Avenue: north from 38th showing offices and apartments; north from 41st street, showing office buildings lining the street.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Streets, Avenues -- Park, [1865-1961] (Box 41)
    Identifier:PR-065-0478
    Park Avenue: church, Y.M.C.A. and Academy of Design, at 23rd looking south; Stewart's Home for women at 32nd and Park, with railroad cars in the foreground; from 33rd Street, small park at right; row of houses with stoops at 41st Street; looking south from 34th, with traffic emerging from underpass; building at 36th and Park; looking north from 34th, Met Life (Pan Am) building in the distance; houses at 36th-37th Streets, with fenced park in front; north from 37th, Chrysler building just visible; north from 37th, Met Life building in distance; west side north from between 46th and 47th; north from 47th right over the park in the middle of the street' north from 49th Street; north from 51st Street; looking up at the nearly complete 375 Park Avenue; looking north from 52nd Street; Christmas tree at Park and 53rd; building on northeast corner of Park and 55th, with sign advertising new office building to be built on the site; north from 78th Street showing plantings in middle; railroad trestle during construction of stone viaduct ("the Fourth Avenue Improvement"), south from 116th Street.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Streets, Avenues -- Vanderbilt, 1959 (Box 41)
    Identifier:PR-065-0479
    Looking north on Vanderbilt Avenue from 42nd Street, Grand Central Station and the Met Life building at right, building under construction at the end of the street.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Railroads, [1870-1933] (Box 41)
    Identifier:PR-065-0480
    Railroads: horses pulling freight cars down the Bowery; view of freight cars from above, looking down between buildings; New York Central Railroad train on a N.Y. street.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Railroads -- Depots, [1867-1871] (Box 41)
    Identifier:PR-065-0481
    Looking north from the Hudson River Railroad station, St. John's Place, railroad car in street; Hudson River R.R. freight station, [designed by John B. Snook] Hudson Street, one view showing the bronze of Vanderbilt and the bas-relief along the pediment.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Railroads -- Depots -- Grand Central, 1871, [1870-1885] (Box 41)
    Identifier:PR-065-0482
    Views of the first Grand Central Station at 42nd Street, including a view of the construction of the train shed, interior views of the train shed, some showing trains in the station; exterior views showing the front of the building with elevated railroad station, horse-drawn omnibuses and carriages in front; from Madison Avenue, with Dr. Tyng's church in foreground; a full length view along Vanderbilt (?); views of an exhibition for Eastman Kodak of the "Chemistry of Kodacolor" located on the balcony of the station.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Railroads -- Depots -- Grand Central, 1913, 1925-1957 (Box 41)
    Identifier:PR-065-0483
    Views of Grand Central Station, completed in 1913: looking at façade from Park Avenue; façade from 42nd Street; interior view looking east, beam of light coming from the south; interior view showing Redstone rocket on display in front of Kodak advertisement.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Railroads -- Depots -- Pennsylvania Station, [1930-1957] (Box 41)
    Identifier:PR-065-0484
    Pennsylvania Station, (1910-1963): interior views showing lobby area and stairs leading to trains; ticket office area, and a later view showing modern ticket office built within older structure; exterior view, looking north along 7th Avenue.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Railroads, Elevated, [1878-1957] (Box 41)
    Identifier:PR-065-0485
    Views of elevated train tracks and cars, including views from above, and from street level, some showing trains on the tracks; includes views on Church and Greenwich streets; views in the engine depot; interior views of BMT cars numbered: 139, 202, 757, 1393, showing conductor, and passengers; cars in the 37th Street yard, and the 239th Street yard.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Railroads, Elevated -- Stations, [1880-1955] (Box 42)
    Identifier:PR-065-0486
    Elevated railroad stations: from above, from the platform, including view showing woman and policeman, from the street; in lower Manhattan, at Greenwich Street, at 42nd Street on the 3rd Ave. line, with large modern building under construction above it; 1st Street and First Avenue, 2nd Avenue line.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Railroads, Elevated -- Third Avenue Line, [1880-1955] (Box 42)
    Identifier:PR-065-0487
    View on the Third Avenue elevated railroad line: from Bayard Street; stairway to City Hall Station; City Hall Branch from Chatham Square station; train at City Hall Station; City Hall Branch from South Ferry tracks; Park Row, looking south from about Baxter Street; Hanover Square; under the "el' at Pearl, north from Beekman; above Second Avenue at St. James Place; north from Canal Street station; in Cooper Square, including views of Cooper Union; north from 34th Street station; north from 42nd Street station; views of stations including the 14th Street, 34th Street, with the Chrysler building in the distance, the 42nd Street and the 59th Street, with a sign for Bloomingdales atop it; view of the skyline, looking south from 53rd Street, Chrysler building in the distance; views of the Third Ave. line being demolished.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Railroads, Elevated -- Sixth Avenue Line, [1885-1900] (Box 42)
    Identifier:PR-065-0488
    Views along the Sixth Avenue elevated railroad line: showing street lined with businesses; views under the tracks showing buildings and wagons.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Railroads, Elevated -- Battery Park, [1880s] (Box 42)
    Identifier:PR-065-0489
    Women and children in Battery Park, with the elevated railroad behind them; view of the train, with steps leading down to the park; train at South Ferry; Battery Park elevated station; view north from Battery Place up Greenwich Street.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Railroads, Elevated -- Chatham Square, [1870-1885] (Box 42)
    Identifier:PR-065-0490
    Views of the elevated railroad at Chatham Square: train at station; train rounding curve; trains at junction; Chatham Square curve from below the tracks.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Railroads, elevated -- Coenties Slip, [1880-1900] (Box 42)
    Identifier:PR-065-0491
    The 's' curve of the elevated railroad at Coenties slip, from above, including view with train, and from street level.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Railroads, elevated -- Northern Manhattan, [1880-1940] (Box 42)
    Identifier:PR-065-0492
    Elevated railroad tracks in northern Manhattan, including the curve at 110th Street, the 6th-9th Avenue line north from just above 116th Street, and the depot at 116th.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Advertising, [1870-1890] (Box 42)
    Identifier:PR-065-0493
    Advertising posters: shoe shine boys standing in front of wall covered with advertising for theaters and Barnum's Museum; walls covered with advertising for Bryant's Minstrels, Wallack's and other theaters.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Architectural details, 1953-1962 (Box 42)
    Identifier:PR-065-0494
    House of Peter de Guard, a furniture store on E. 51st showing decorated pediment and awning; cast iron fronts of worth Street W. of Broadway.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Balloons, [1860s] (Box 42)
    Identifier:PR-065-0495
    Ascent of Professor Low's Balloon from the corner of 6th Avenue and 59th Street (Central Park in background).
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Building construction, [1907-1961] (Box 42)
    Identifier:PR-065-0496
    Building construction: the Singer building from the North tower of the Park Row building, with dome and statues in foreground; Metropolitan Life tower under construction showing steel beams; photographer from H.C. White Co. perched atop a steel column of building under construction; building under construction, from Third Avenue Line's 42nd street elevated station, showing site over time starting with parking lot, showing excavation, foundations, steel frame rising, and placement of floors; excavation for Time and Life Building, Sixth Avenue and 50th Street; First National City Bank building under construction, 53rd and Lexington, skyline beyond; scaffolding on buildings along Pine Street from William Street.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Chinatown, 1925-1951 (Box 42)
    Identifier:PR-065-0497
    Street views in Chinatown, showing shops and signs in Chinese; market at the corner of Worth, Mott and Park Row.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Fairs and Festivals, 1951 (Box 42)
    Identifier:PR-065-0498
    Views of the San Gennaro Festival on Mulberry Street, 1951, including general views of the street showing decorations and booths, the shrine of San Gennaro, and the Queen of the Feast of San Gennaro.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Fairs and festivals -- American Institute, [1870] (Box 42)
    Identifier:PR-065-0499
    Views of the American Institute of the City of New York National Fair (most views dated 1870): exterior views showing building, and advertisements; interiors including view of photography exhibit, including E. & H.T. Anthony's firm; a soda fountain; general view of the interior of the "Rink" showing exhibit cases; apples on exhibit; view showing furnishings on display; glass and silver on display; scrollwork.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Fairs and festivals -- Metropolitan Sanitary Fair, 1864 (Box 43)
    Identifier:PR-065-0500
    Great Metropolitan Sanitary Fair: exterior views of buildings in Union Square and views along 14th Street, including "the Knickerbocker Kitchen," the Art Gallery; interiors: paintings and sculpture, including "Washington Crossing the Delaware"; coconut tree amid the displays in the main building; Arms and trophy room, showing display cases, suit of armor, captured swords and blunderbusses and a Confederate flag; the Firemen's department including busts and a quilt; west entry to principal room showing bunting, flags, and taxidermy; Ohio stand; entrance to Irving's summer house, "Cockloft Hall"; looking across the main hall; stands of glassware; surgical and optical department; Machinery department; marine department showing models of ships including the Isaac Newton; sword given to U.S. Grant; guards standing by entrance to diorama and miniature battle field; floral arrangements; New Jersey department; displays representing the four seasons.
    52 items
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Fairs and festivals -- World's Fair, 1939 (Box 43)
    Identifier:PR-065-0501
    The New York World's Fair of 1939-1940: views of the grounds, including from the Long Island Railroad Station; from the Perisphere; the Perisphere, one view with elephants in the pool; Lagoon of Nations fountains; Constitution Mall including the sundial and the Washington statue; Avenue of Pioneers, with flags of various nations; Bowling Green Fountain; Communications building; national exhibits, including the (U.S.S.R.) Russian, Chilean, French, Italian, Polish, Portuguese, British Empire, and Belgian buildings and exhibits including pools and birds at the Brazilian, dioramas at the Netherlands, Belgian tapestries, Irish linen, Mexican antiquities, general views of the French, Swedish, Canadian, Thai, Venezuelan and U.S.S.R. exhibits; looking through a waterfall at the Italian exhibit; Japanese exhibit, including pearl Liberty Bell; state exhibits, including New England Building and Yankee whaler; Court of State and the Virginia building, and exhibits including a pioneer cabin at the Missouri exhibit, fire engine at N.Y. city exhibit, general view of N.Y. State exhibit and diorama of Niagara Falls, diorama of birds at Florida exhibit, diorama of cotton at Georgia exhibit; industry exhibits including the Consolidated Edison, Eastman Kodak, National Cash Register, Ford, American Telephone and Telegraph, General Electric, United States Steel, Electrical Utilities and Petroleum industry buildings and exhibits including railroad miniatures and other railroad exhibits including the "DeWitt Clinton" locomotive and other trains, tomato plants at H.J. Heinz, General Motors Futurama, diorama at Con Ed, the Chase and Sanborn exhibit, milking a cow at the Borden exhibit; Glass industry's mirrored ceiling and distortion mirrors, Gardens on display exhibit; gardens and restaurants; amusements, including the sideshow and parachute jump; Billy Rose Aquacade performance.
    100 items
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Fire fighting, [1859 - 1870] (Box 43)
    Identifier:PR-065-0502
    Fires and fire fighting equipment: men with steam fire engine; fire engine standing on street of row houses; men with fire engine hose carriage on the corner of 13th Street and Broadway; men fighting the fire at Cyrus W. Field's warehouse, crowds in the foreground, hoses in the street.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Harlem, [1920s] (Box 43)
    Identifier:PR-065-0503
    A street in Harlem, showing homes, a dance studio, beauty parlor, the Ethiopian World Federation and a theater (the Renaissance).
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Holiday decorations, 1953-1963 (Box 43)
    Identifier:PR-065-0504
    Christmas decorations: the tree at Rockefeller center; decorations inside the ground floor of Macy's department store; decorations over the entrance and along the façade of Macy's department store.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Immigration, [1880 - 1920] (Box 43)
    Identifier:PR-065-0505
    Immigration: a group of immigrant men on a wagon; Ellis Island, with line of immigrants waiting outside the station; Ellis Island, showing buildings and ferry at dock.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Lower East Side, [1900 - 1905] (Box 43)
    Identifier:PR-065-0506
    Lower East Side: street scenes in the Lower East side, including children, street vendors, shops and fire escapes with laundry hanging out.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Parades, 1859-1900 (Box 44)
    Identifier:PR-065-0507
    Parades in Manhattan: parades on unidentified occasions, including views near the Hall of Records, looking up 5th Avenue from 23rd Street, Broadway from about Franklin Street, and a parade on Fifth Avenue in honor of Admiral Dewey; Peace procession (Civil War?) on Broadway; a circus parade; the parade for the Atlantic Telegraph Jubilee, showing Broadway; Fourth of July parade, 1860, showing infantry, cavalry, and Highlanders on Tyron Row; parade near Union Square for reception of the Grand Duke Alexis, 1871; peace between Germany and France, 1871; parade for the opening of the new Masonic Temple, June 1875; Decoration Day, 1876, view showing Broadway, and Stewart's store; military units marching on Decoration day, 1888; Macy's Thanksgiving Day Parade, 1951, showing the Mighty Mouse and Dachshund balloons, and a Warner-Pathe newsreel units on 34th outside Macy's after the parade.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Parades, Japanese Embassy, 1860 (Box 44)
    Identifier:PR-065-0508
    Japanese Embassy, June 6, 1860: views of the parade, including views looking up and down Broadway, before and during the parade, with Japanese and American flags visible hanging from buildings, military units, including the 7th and 8th Regiments and cavalry, views shot from rooftops, showing the parade route, including a nearby church, as well as spectators on the roof, and men and women peering over the edge; guns ready to fire the salute [at the Battery?]; crowds gathering at City Hall; also includes portraits of Cavasaki Doming [sic], doctor, and other members of the Embassy.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Parades, Lincoln's funeral, 1865 (Box 44)
    Identifier:PR-065-0509
    Lincoln's funeral procession on Broadway, April 25, 1865: military units including artillery, and the catafalque bearing Lincoln's body; crowds lining the street and American flags overhead; includes views of City Hall, decorated outside, and interior view showing entrance to catafalque.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Parades, Labor Day, 1887 (Box 44)
    Identifier:PR-065-0510
    Labor Day parade, 1887, at Union Square: groups of workers making a turn at Union Square, including a wagon of workers with a banner reading "Fortitude Association of NY Tobacco Workers," and a band leading a group all with white hats.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Parades, Centennial, 1889 (Box 44)
    Identifier:PR-065-0511
    U.S. Constitution Centennial celebration: decoration on Wall Street; parades on April 30 and May 1, including military units (incl. the 3rd Pennsylvania Regiment, the 22nd regiment), firemen, floats, including one made to look like Faneuil Hall; art and trades exhibits in the Citizen's Parade; most views made near Union Square, showing large crowds in attendance.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Parades, Columbus Day, 1892 (Box 44)
    Identifier:PR-065-0512
    Columbus parade, 1892: looking north from 23rd Street, Fifth Avenue Hotel; 22nd Regiment, N.Y. National Guard; West Point cadets; decorated arches; crowds.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Parades, Dewey, 1899 (Box 44)
    Identifier:PR-065-0513
    Parade in honor of Admiral George Dewey, and the end of the Spanish American War: views of the Dewey Triumphal Arch on Fifth Avenue, including one view from the fifth Avenue Hotel, with Madison Square Garden in the distance, and with crowds and troops nearby; the Tenth Pennsylvania Regiment, the Tenth U.S. Cavalry; 7th regiment, N.Y. National Guard; "Wendell's Battery," with Grant's Tomb in the background, "sea fighters" from the Olympia, Dewey's flagship, 23rd Regiment, N.G.N.Y.; West Point Cadets.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Parades, World War I, 1919 (Box 44)
    Identifier:PR-065-0514
    Parade on Fifth Avenue at the end of World War I, including a "triumphal arc," huge crowds, soldiers from the 27th Division, flags and bunting hanging from buildings.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Police, [1900] (Box 44)
    Identifier:PR-065-0515
    Group of police going on duty in lower Manhattan; "Broadway Squad," mounted police on Broadway.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Shanties, [1870s] (Box 44)
    Identifier:PR-065-0516
    Copy photograph of group of people near shanties, possibly Park Avenue and 50th.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Sidewalk activities, 1932-1952 (Box 44)
    Identifier:PR-065-0517
    Washington Square south during Outdoor Art Show, May 1932; artist at work on the sidewalk, 1950; women and ice cream vendor at Village Art show, 1950; artists and viewers at Greenwich Village art show, 1950; men at hot dog cart, 45th, between Park and Lexington Avenue; hot dog cart on 14th and 8th Avenue.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Television, 1940-1962 (Box 44)
    Identifier:PR-065-0518
    Television in New York: television truck, and talent search at the New York World's Fair; R.C.A. Electronics exhibit, including television demonstration, 40, W. 49th Street; WJZ T.V. truck outside Macy's after parade, 1951; woman looking at Videcon TV camera at Chemical Exposition, 1951; views of the set of the TV program "This is Show Business showing cameras and other equipment, and advertisements hanging up behind panel members; N.B.C. color television mobile unit, a large van with camera on top at Rockefeller center outside the color TV exhibit; views inside the exhibit, including views of television camera tubes, and picture tubes; crowd watching the Dave Garaway show outside Rockefeller Center; N.B.C. Mobile unit rigged on top a car, on Fifth Avenue; various businesses advertising color TV, including a tavern, and a combination fortune telling and television repair shop; a skyscraper under construction, showing the "sidewalk superintendents'" TV receiver on Lexington Avenue, at the Western Electric Building, in window of A.T.and T. building, 195 Broadway and of the construction of the Pan Am building; Ampex TV tape recorder on exhibit at Merrill, Lynch, Pierce, Fenner, and Smith at Grand Central Station; old Al Jolson Theater, being used as a videotape center; the Avon theater, with marquee reading "Network Television Preview Theatre"; model of TV satellite "Tiros" at R.C.A. exhibition hall; N.B.C. color TV cameras outside Macy's after the parade, 1961; C.B.S. television projector at Grand Central Station, used to project broadcast Glenn space flight on screen on top of ticket windows; looking down on set of R.C.A. color TV studio, New York World's Fair, 1964.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Turkish baths, [1890] (Box 45)
    Identifier:PR-065-0519
    Interior view of "reclining room" at Everard's Turkish Baths, 28 West 28th Street showing leather couches, a desk, and a fountain.
  - New York--NYC -- Manhattan--Topics -- Window displays, 1940-1964 (Box 45)
    Identifier:PR-065-0520
    Window displays: a window in Gimbel's with small sculpture of a fawn, and men's shirts; boxes of flowers outside wholesale florists on 6th Avenue; Chinchilla Promotion Agency on Broadway, with neon chinchillas in window; Universal Atomics, advertising transistorized instruments, and with a small sign reading "strike uranium in Catskill Mtns"; Bannerman Fire Arms, military good from Government auction, 501 Broadway; Sam Goody Record shop, 235 W. 49th; Tin Pan Alley Records, advertising stereo tapes and discs; window for "Flowers by Katya" on 8th Avenue; Olevetti typewriter display, showing single typewriter on column set in the sidewalk, Fifth Avenue; the sculpture "Windward" at 200 E. 42nd.
  - New York--NYC -- Brooklyn, [1860-1953] (Box 45)
    Identifier:PR-065-0521